Guide to the Stanislaw Czamanski papers, 1942-1990
Czamanski, Stanislaw Papers, 1942-1990
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Stanislaw Czamanski papers, 1942-1990
15-2-2293
Stanislaw Czamanski.
10.5 cubic ft.
Curriculum vitae, drafts of speeches, lecture and teaching notes, reports, research projects, typescripts of articles, published articles, manuscripts, and reprints.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Curriculum vitae, drafts of speeches, lecture and teaching notes, reports, research projects, typescripts of articles, published articles, manuscripts, and reprints about regional planning and regional science.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Stanislaw Czamanski was a professor of city and regional planning at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Curriculum vitae, drafts of speeches, lecture and teaching notes, reports, research projects, typescripts of articles, published articles, manuscripts, and reprints about regional planning and regional science. Some materials are in Polish.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Czamanski, Stanislaw.
Subjects:
City planning--United States.; City planning--Poland.; Regional planning.; Regional science.
Form and Genre Terms:
Resumes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Drafts of speeches, reprints, reports, and research projects., c. 1950-1982 (Box 1-3)
  - "A Model of Urban Growth", by Stanislaw Czamanski, University of Pennsylvania., c. 1967 (Box 3)
  - Reprint from The Canadian Journal of Economics: "Regional Social Accounts: Nova Scotia, 1961-1964", Stanislaw Czamanski, Cornell University., c. 1969 (Box 3)
  - Community Renewal Program, Baltimore Urban Renewal and Housing Agency. Economic Growth Forecast of Baltimore. Stage Two, Staff Monograph 22, 8b., December 1964 (Box 3)
  - Community Renewal Program, Baltimore Urban Renewal and Housing Agency. Industrial Activities. Stage Two, Staff Monograph 22, 8b., May 1965 (Box 3)
  - Reprint from The Town Planning Review. "Industrial Location and Urban Growth", by Stanislaw Czamanski, Vol. 36, No. 3., October 1965 (Box 3)
  - Reprint from the Journal of Regional Science, "A Method of Forecasting Metropolitan Growth by Means of Distributed Lags Analysis." Vol. 6, No. 1., 1965 (Box 3)
  - Papers of the Regional Science Association, Vol. 27. "Some Empirical Evidence of the Strengths of Linkages Between Groups of Related Industries in Urban-Regional Complexes." Stan Czamanski, Cornell University. (Box 3)
  - Peace Research Society: Papers, v. Philadelphia Conference, "A Model for the Projection of Regional Industrial Structure, Land Use Patterns and Conversion Potentialities", by Walter Isard and Stanislaw Czamanski., 1966 (Box 3)
  - Draft. "Regional Science, Regional Planning and Geography", by Stanislaw Czamanski, Cornell University., February 1-2, 1967 (Box 3)
    A paper prepared for the Conference on Geography and Planning, sponsored by the Graduate Program in Planning, University of Puerto Rico, Rio Piedras, Puerto Rico.
  - Reprint. "The Evolving Epistmology of Regional Science", November 1975 (Box 3)
    Presidential Address to Annual Meeting of the Regional Science Association, Cambridge, Massachusetts. Stan Czamanski, Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., and Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia.
  - Sixteenth European Congress of the Regional Science Association. "Industrial Complexes: Their Typology, Structure, and Relation to Economic Development", by Daniel Z. Czamanski and Stan Czamanski., 1977 (Box 3)
  - Journal of Regional Science, "Needless Complexity in the Identification of Industrial Complexes: A Comment", by Stan Czamanski. Vol. 17, No. 3., 1977 (Box 3)
  - Urban Studies. "Identification of Industrial Clusters and Complexes: A Comparison of Methods and Findings", by Stan Czamanski and Luiz Augusto de Q. Ablas., 1979 (Box 3)
- Typescripts of articles, published articles, and manuscripts., 1942-1984 (Box 4-9)
  - "A Dynamic Programming Model of Regional Industrial Development", by Stanislaw Czamanski and Ian Taft., Aprril 1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "The Effects of Wage Structure upon Industrial Development", by Stanislaw Czamanski and Hebrew University, Mar. 1984; "Macro vs. Micro Approaches to Regional Industrialization Planning: The Case of Western Galilee." Stanislaw Czamanski and Technion, Haifa, Israel. n.d., but publication date set for 1989. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "The Evolving Epistemology of Regional Science" and "A Fused System of Regional Accounts", by Stanislaw Czamanski., November 1975; April 1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Identification of Industrial Clusters and Complexes: A Comparison of Methods and Findings", by Stanislaw Czamanski and Luiz Augusto de Q. Ablas., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "The Impact of Foreign Trade Policies upon Industrial Structure", and "Dynamic Models of Industrial Development", by Stanislaw Czamanski., December 1979-January 1980; July 1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "On a Class of Quasi Demand Functions for Certain Urban Public Services", by Stanislaw Czamanski., 1975 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Regional Policy Planning: Some Possible Implications for Research", by Stanislaw Czamanski., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Regional Science, Regional Planning and Geography", by Stanislaw Czamanski., February 1967; March 1968 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Research Proposal: "A Study of Industrial Settlement Patterns in Israel", by Stanislaw Czamanski and Alexander Cohen. Rehovot., March 1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "Some Aspects of the Supply of Labor to Rural Industries", by Stanislaw Czamanski and Raphael Bar-El., October 1983 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "Some Considerations Concerning the Economic Base Theory", by Stanislaw Czamanski. Haifa, Israel. Institute of Public Affairs of Dalhousie University Contract for Pilot Research Area. (Nine Nova Scotian Counties.), June 1958 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - List of Publications and Research Papers (most titles translated) by Stanislaw Czamanski., July 1963 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Regional Social Accounting: A Case Approach", by Stanislaw Czamanski.., December 1966; June 1967 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Lodzki Okreg Przemyslowy. "Obrot Towarowy". Pracownia Planow Regionalnych w Lodzi., 1954 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - "Funkoja L.O.P. Skali Krajowej I Regionalnej." Pracownia Planow Regionalnych w Lodzi. Ludwik Straszewicz., 1954 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Hipoteza. "Rozwoju prezemyslu w Okresie Perpektywicznym na Terenie m. Zgierza," by Stanislaw Czamanski., 1957 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Lodzki Okreg Przemyslowy Wstepna Koncepcja Ukladu Osiedlenczego." Pracownia Planow Regionalnych w Lodzi, by Stanislaw Czamanski., 1954 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - "Plan Regionalny Lodzkiego Okregri Przemysewego Program Inwestycji." Opracowanie Pracowni Planow Regionalnych w Lodzi Wykenal mgr. Stanislaw Czamanski. Ludwik Straszewicz, Kierownik Pracowni Planow Regionalnych w Lodzi., 1954 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - "Przemysl." Pracownia Planow Regionalnych. Wykenal mgr. Stanislaw Czamanski, Opracowanie Pracowni Planow Regionalnych w Lodzi. Ludwik Straszewicz, Kierownik Pracowni Planow Regionalnych w Lodzi., 1954 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - "Some Considerations Concerning the Economic Base Theory", by Stanislaw Czamanski. Haifa, Israel., 1958 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - "Methodological Aspects and Issues of Regional Planning." Teaching material prepared by Stanislaw Czamanski., 1974 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Trabalho Para Discussao Intenna No. 06/76, by Stanislaw Czamanski, Luiz Augusto de Q. Ablas, Martin Lu, and Juarez Rizzieri. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Materialy do Kursow Planowania Gospodarki Norodowej, Czesc III. (Material for National Economic Planning Courses, Part III.) Warsaw, Poland,. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - "Inwentaryzacja Srodkow Trwalych." ("Stock taking of Investments in Infrastructure.") by B.I. Piestraiakow., 1952 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Okreslenie Kowztow Budowy Elementow Miasta. Institute of Urban Studies and Architecture, Warsaw., 1954 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Piotrkow Trybunalski. Plan Ogolny Perspektywiczny i Etapowy. (General Development Plan of Piotrkow Trybunalski - long term and first stage.), 1957 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Plan Porzadkowania Miasta (Planning the Rebuilding of a Devastated City.), 1956 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Plan pracy, "Powstanie i Rozway Lodzkiego Prezemyslu Wlokienniczego." (Plan and outline of a monograph: "Origins and Development of the Lodz Textile Industry.") Stanislaw Czamanski with J. Sierputowski., c. 1956 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Przemysl Wlokienniczy (Textile industry in the Lodz Industrial Region). Characteristic features and the role of the Lodz textile industry in the national economy. The enclosed is a draft, later published in a different form, c. 1952 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Przemsl Wlokienniczy (Textile industry in the Lodz Industrial Region). Views and opinions of various decision makers and authorities., c. 1956 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Profile Spoiczno-Gospodarcze w Planowaniu Handlu. (Socio-economic profiles for planning of retail networks.), 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Project Normatywy I Wskazan Urbanistycznych dla Planow Ogolnych. (Proposed standards and indices for general urban plans.), n.d. (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Tymczasowe Normatywy Urbanistyczne Dla Projecktowania Miast i Osiedli. (Provisional Standards for planning cities and settlements)., 1951 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Zbior Przepism z Dziedzing Urbanistyki (Review of Town Planning Regulations.)., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Zalozenia Programowe do I-azej Fazy Ogolnego perspektywicznego i Etapowego Planu Zagospodarowania Przestrzennego. (Assumptions for preparing the first phase of a General long term plan and its first stage.) Halina Grabowska., c. 1952 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Zalozenia Programowe Parkow Ludowych (Parkow Kutury.) (Planning Standards for Amusement Parks. Series, Part 14. Institute of Urban Studies and Architecture.), 1953 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Lecture and teaching notes., 1956-1995 (Box 10-11)